CHRISTOPHER ELLIS

Salt Lake City, UT 84109 **Phone:** 385,421,0733

Email: christopher.ryan.ellis@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-ellis-b018a67/ GitHub: https://github.com/Arnette110

Portfolio: https://arnette110.github.io/Updated-Portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in Customer Service and experience in database management and business operations. Reliable and successful in setting priorities and meeting deadlines. Detail oriented, with devotion to accuracy and efficiency.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Applications: Microsoft & Mac platforms, VSCode, GitBash, MySQL Workbench, Robo-3T **Languages/Frameworks/Libraries:** HTML5, CSS3/Bootstrap/Bulma, JavaScript/jQuery, AJAX/axios, Node.js, Express.js, handlebars.js, MySQL/Sequelize, MongoDB/mongoose, React.js

RECENT PROJECTS

Stock Watcher!

<u>GitHub - https://github.com/Arnette110/stock-shares-viewer</u> <u>Deployed - https://guiet-scrubland-40925.herokuapp.com/</u>

- This is a stock watchlist building app created under the MVC paradigm.
- Responsible for the final layout and design.
- Implemented use of CanvasJS for displaying JSON data as a candlestick chart.
- Assisted in setting up API routes to the database.
- Created with Node.js, Express.js, MySQL/Sequelize, AJAX/axios, CanvasJS, popupS.js, HTML, Bulma, JavaScript/jQuery.

GalactChris Devourer of Burgers

<u>GitHub - https://github.com/Arnette110/GalactChris-devourer-of-burgers</u> Deployed - https://sheltered-citadel-94305.herokuapp.com/

- An MVC paradigm app that allows a user to order a burger and devour it, re-order it or delete it from the db.
- Responsible for all aspects of the project.
- Created with Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, handlebars.js, CSS/Bulma, JavaScript/jQuery/AJAX.

Employee DireActory

<u>GitHub - https://github.com/Arnette110/Employee-DireActory</u> Deployed - https://arnette110.github.io/Employee-DireActory/

- A dynamically updated employee directory table.
- Responsible for all aspects of the project.
- Created with React/JSX, Bulma, Javascript

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tire/Alignment Technician

Foothill Tire Pros | March 2018 - Current

Completes all aspects of changing tires on customer vehicles

Performs alignment adjustments

Coordinates with other team members to ensure efficiency and accuracy of work

Tele-Underwriter

Equitable Life and Casualty | April 2015 - December 2016

Performed medical underwriting interviews with insurance applicants; inbound and outbound calls

Provided assistance and guidance to Agents and Co-workers with underwriting inquiries

Assisted QA department with usability testing of new software

Received Employee of the Week Award for outstanding performance and service multiple times

Client Manager

Chartlogic, Inc | June 2013 - February 2015

Educated clients on the effective use of Chartlogic software

Proactively reached out to clients to resolve software challenges and create prompt resolution plans

Provided troubleshooting support for incoming issue calls; actively listened to client concerns

Performed usability testing for software updates

Upscale Brand Hotel Reservations Sales Agent (English/German Speaking)

Intercontinental Hotels Group | September 2009 – June 2013

Sold five-star hotel room accommodations and paid loyalty programs to travelers

Consistently ranked among the top performers in the department (10% above peers weekly)

Received multiple Intercontinental Elite awards for recognition of top performance

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT (in progress)

A 24-week intensive, Full Stack Web Development, program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.js.

Bachelor of Arts Degree: University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT

A degree in the field of International Studies with an emphasis on the study of International Business and German Linguistics.

<u>Undergraduate Coursework: Christian Albrechts Universität zu Kiel, Kiel, Schleswig-Holstein, Germany</u> Undergraduate summer study in German linguistics and culture.